Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (VADP); Records apap304
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1937-2007; 7; 6.05 cubic ft.
  - Indigent Counsel, 2002-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Indigent Defense in the USA, 2002-2003; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Indigent Defense in Virginia, 2006 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Ineffective Assistance of Counsel, 2002-2003 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Ineffective Counsel, 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - In Lieu of Flowers, 2007 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Innocence, 2003 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - Innocence and the DP, 1999-2000; 2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - Innocence Project of the National Capital Region, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - Innocence Protection Act, 2001-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 75)
  - Institute for Actual Innocence, 2007 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 76)
  - International Death Penalty, 2003-2004 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 77)
  - International Justice Project Equal Protection and Expanded Guide, Undated (Cd 2)
  - International Juvenile DP, 2002 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 78)
  - International Prayer for Peace, 2006 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Imagine Festival, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Iron and the Death Penalty, 2002-2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - "Is He too Young to Die", 1995 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Italy Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Jack Hicks, 2005 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - James Reid, 1996; 2001; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Joe Giarratano, 1991; 2000; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - John Warner, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Jordan Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Journey of Hope, 1995 (Video-tape 19)
  - Just Children, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - The Justice Project, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Justice Stevens, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Juvenile Corrections in Iraq, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty, 2000; 2002-2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty, 2003-2004; 2006; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Book Mark, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Cases, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Curriculum, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Materials, 2004-2005 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Packet Draft, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Resolution Draft, 2003; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Resources, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Juvenile DP Articles, 1985; 1987-1992; 2004-2005; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Juvenile DP Fact Sheet, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Juvenile DP Initiative, 2004-2005; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Juvenile Execution Materials, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Juvenile Murder Cases, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Kaine, 2007 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Kansas Cherley, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Kentucky Death Penalty, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Kerry Cook, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Kids Death Penalty Answers, 2002 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - "Killers", 1937 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - King DP Sermon, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Lack of Benefits of the Death Penalty, 1989 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Lapeine De Mort, 2006 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Larry King Sniper Trials, Undated (Video-tape 20)
  - "The Legacy of Wrongful Convictions ", 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Legality of Execution, 2002 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Legislative Prep Materials, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Legislative Strategy Template, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Lethal Injections, 1998; 2005-2006 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Lethal Injections Articles, 1982; 1985-1999; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Lethal Injections Articles, 1998; 1990; 1995-1998 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Lethal Injections Debate, 1993-1994; 1998 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Lethal Injections Research, 1980-1982; 1988; 2004-2005; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Liberty Prison Outreach The Choice is Yours, Undated (Video-tape 20)
  - Life on Death Row, 1980 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - "Life Without Fear", 2002 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - List of Inmates, Undated; 1987 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Martinsville Seven, 2004; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Maryland Death Penalty, 2002-2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Massachusetts Death Penalty, 2002-2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Mental Illness and the Death Penalty, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Mental Retardation and the Death Penalty, 1999; 2002; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Mexicans on Death Row, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Mexico Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Mexico v. USA, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Michael Graham, 2001 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Michael Morales, 2006 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Michigan Death Penalty, 2002 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Miller-EL, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Miscarriage of Justice, 1995 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Missouri Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Moral Arguments Against the Death Penalty, 1986 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Morality and the DP, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Moratorium and Religion, 1987; 1991; 1998-2001; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Moratorium in other States, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Moratorium Now! Materials, 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Moratorium Study, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Morocco Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - Moussaoui Trial, 2006 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - MVFR Exhibit Loan, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - Muhammad and Malvo, Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Native Americans Death Penalty, 1993; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - NCADP Flyers and Handouts, 2004; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 75)
  - NC Death Penalty Cases, 1993-1994; 1999-2000 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 76)
  - Nebraska Death Penalty, 2002 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 77)
  - Nelson v. Campbell, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 78)
  - Nevada Death Penalty, 2002-2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 79)
  - New Hampshire Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 80)
  - New Jersey Moratorium, 2006 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 81)
  - New York Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 82)
  - New Yorkers Against the Death Penalty, 2005 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 83)
  - Nicholas Yarris, 2004 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 84)
  - Non Jury Sentencing, 2003 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 85)
  - Norfolk Rape Murder, 2002 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 86)
  - North Carolina Death Penalty, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Ohio Death Penalty, 2002-2003 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Ohio Moratorium Materials, 2005 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Oklahoma Death Penalty, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Opposition in Virginia, Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Organizing the Alternatives, VADP Annual Conference (Oct. 25, 2003) (Video-tape 21)
  - Paul Akers, 2006 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Pat Robertson, 2000 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - People of Faith, 2006 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Prison Industrial Complex, 2003-2004 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Prison Life in USA, 2002 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Prisons and Rehabilitation, Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Popular Opinion, Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Post Conviction Evidence, 2002 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Plea Bargain Articles, 2004 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Pleading Guilty, 2002-2003; Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Post Cards, Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Posthumous Exoneration, 2006 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Powell, 1989 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - The Practice Tape #2, Undated (Video-tape 22)
  - Pre- Journey, Ga., Undated (Video-tape 23)
  - Pro-Death Penalty Articles, 2003 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Prosecution Misconduct, 2003-2004 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Puerto Rico Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Push for Expanded list of Capital Crime, 2007 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Race and The Death Penalty, 2000-2001; 2002-2003; Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Raise the Roof Demand Government Action for Human Rights, Undated (Video-tape 24)
  - Rally in Richmond (Feb. 9, 1991) (Video-tape 25)
  - Ray Krone, 2002 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Red Onion Commissary Order Form, 2004 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Religion and the Death Penalty, 1994-1995; 1997; 1999-2000 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Religion Services WRIC-TV (Feb. 12-17, 1995) (Video-tape 26)
  - Report on Trials, 2003 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Resource Guide to Community Organizations, 2003 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - "Rights of the Child", 2002 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Roger Coleman, 1992 (Video-tape 27)
  - Roper v. Simmons Articles, 2004 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - "Rules for Segregation and Progressive Housing", Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Saudi Arabia Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - SB 333 Suggestions, 2004; Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Schriro vs. Summerlin Ruling, 2004 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Debate v. Allen, 2004 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Senator Robb, 1994; Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Sentences Hit 30 Year Low, 2004 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Southern Poverty Law Death Penalty Tape, Undated (Video-tape 28)
  - Spectrum of Positions and Allies, Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Stop Killing Kids, 1992 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Students against the DP, 2003 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Supreme Court, 1992; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Talk America, Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Tennessee Death Penalty, 2002-2003 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Terrorism and the DP, 2001 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Texas Death Penalty, 2002-2006; Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Texas Defense Act, 2003 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - This Far by Faith Materials, 2004 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Trigger man Veto, 2007 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - "The Truth About an Eye for an Eye", 1977 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - "Unheard Voices", 2003 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - United Methodist Church, 2005; Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - University of Richmond, Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - US and Juvenile DP, 2002-2004; Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - US Congress and the Death Penalty, Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - US Execution Statistics, 1999 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - US Exonerations, 1992; 2003-2004 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - USA Death Penalty Statistics, Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Utah Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - VA Crime Commission, 2003-2004 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - VADP Annual Conference Restorative Justice and the Death Penalty, 2005 (Video-tape 29)
  - VADP Banquet Part One, 1999 (Video-tape 30)
  - VADP Banquet Part Two, 1999 (Video-tape 31)
  - VADP Banquet Photos, 1999; 2001 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - VADP License Plate, Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Valley Virginia, 2006 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Victims Families Against the Death Penalty, 1989; 1994-1995; 1997-1999 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Victims Families Reconciliation, 1990; 1997-2000; 2003; Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Virginia Cure, Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Virginia Currents Episode 1002, 2000 (Video-tape 32)
  - Virginia Death Row Inmates, 2000; 2004 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Virginia Democratic Party, 2006 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Virginia Executed, 1991; 1994-1998; 2000-2003; Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Virginia Faith, 1993; 1998; Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Virginia General Assembly Materials, 2006-2008 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Virginia General Assembly Materials, 2007 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Virginia Interfaith Center, 2005-2006 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Virginia Interfaith Center Day for All People of Faith, 2007 (Cd 3)
  - Virginia State Meeting of Amnesty International, 2004 (Cd 4)
  - VOP, 2005-2006 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Washington DC Death Penalty, 1997; 2002 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Watt Espy Winter, 1984-1985 (Video-tape 33)
  - Web Banner, Undated (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - The Week from DPIC, 2006 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Weekly C'ville, 1999 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - When a Parent Goes to Jail, Undated (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Who Gets to Live, 2003 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Why Execute the Retarded, 1988 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Why the Death Penalty Doesn't Work, 1995 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Wiggins v. Smith, 2003 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - William Rehnquist, 2004 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - William Zeigler, 2005 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Willie Lynch Speech, 1999 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Women and the Death Penalty, 1995-1998; Undated (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - World Day Against the DP, 2003 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Wrong on Wrongful Executions, 2006 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Wrongful Conviction, 2002-2004 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Wrongful Conviction Study, 2004 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Wrongful Death Sentences, 2000 (Box 6 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - You Could be Arrested Mid Atlantic Region, Undated (Video-tape 34)
  - Youth Law Center South Dakota State Training School, Undated (Video-tape 35)